Guide to the Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Individuals M-Z, Series II
  - Rankin, Henry W.
    - Twenty-six letters addressed to Rankin. Correspondents include Charles Beecher, Gen. A. W. Greeley, Julian Hawthorne, John Hay, Wm. James, Rudyard Kipling, Walter H. Page, Ida M. Tarbell., 1896- 1931 (Box 179)
  - Reddy, E.S.
    Enuga Sreenivasulu Reddy was born on July 1, 1924, in Pallaprolu, India. From 1936 to 1965, Reddy was the principal secretary for the United Nations Special Committee Against Apartheid. He served as chief of the Section for African Questions from 1965 to 1976. Reddy was the assistant secretary-general of the United Nations from 1983 until his retirement in 1985. See Manuscript and Archives group MS 1499 for the bulk of the E.S. Reddy Papers. This collection, consisting of church-related printed material and correspondence that were transferred to the Divinity Library, complements YDSL RG 105, Washington Office on Africa, and RG 102 Episcopal Churchpeople for a Free Southern Africa.
    - Correspondence: Letters: To Dr. Potter from Leslie Harriman re. apartheid; To Wm. Johnston from Lewis Macfarlane re. Namibian detainees; To E. S. Reddy from Bill Johnston re TV program; To Jimmy Carter from Amb. Donald Sole re. arrest of church leaders; To E. Reddy from Renate Pratt re. Rands for Racism; To E. Reddy from Frank Ferrari re. Desmond Tutu; To Editor N.Y. Post from Wm. Johnston re. Namibia. To Mayer Coleman Yound from Wm. Johnston re. South African Chiefs of Police. To Western 5 Contact Group from Exec.Committee of Council of Churches re. Namibia; To E. S. Reddy from R.J. Rajkumar re. Apartheid Newsletters, 1978-1984 (Box 395, Folder 1)
    - World Council of Churches Programme to Combat Racism Reports and Information Papers #1-3, 6-8, 1-0, 13 re. Namibia, Bank loan/grants, WCC Consultation, etc., 1979-1981 (Box 395, Folder 2-6)
    - Reports, statements, newsletters of other organizations, including Agency for Industrial Mission, Kairos Werkgroep, American Friends Service Committee, Lutheran World Ministries, National Council of Churches, 1970-1982, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 7-8)
    - Press releases, including from United Nations and Episcopal Church Center, etc. re. Bank Campaign Contacts, Sporting Exchanges with South Africa, Desmond Tutu, Namibia, 1973-1989 (Box 395, Folder 9)
    - Newsletters and documentation from Episcopal Churchmen for South Africa / Episcopal Churchpeople for a Free Southern Africa (See also YDSL RG102), 1971-1989 (Box 395, Folder 10-12)
    - Newsletters from ELTSA - End Loans to Southern Africa, 1980-1987 (Box 396, Folder 1)
    - Newsletters from church-related groups re. Namibia, 1982-1986 (Box 396, Folder 2)
    - Documentation re. C. Edward Crowther, Anglican Bishop in South Africa, 1967-1968 (Box 396, Folder 3)
    - Articles and statements re. Church and Southern Africa - National Council of Churches of Christ, Lutheran, Reformed Church of America, 1977-1984 (Box 396, Folder 4)
    - Articles and statements re. Church and Southern Africa - World Council of Churches, 1979-1982 (Box 396, Folder 5-6)
    - Articles and statements re. Church and Southern Africa - United Church of Christ, United Nations, 1969-1972 (Box 396, Folder 7)
    - Articles and statements re. Church and Southern Africa - miscellaneous, 1977-1983 (Box 396, Folder 8-9)
    - Articles and statements re. Church and Southern Africa - miscellaneous, 1977-1990 (Box 282, Folder 17)
    - Transcript of interview and discussions between John R. Mott with Mahatma Gandhi; copies of letters from Gandhi to Mott; copies of letters from Gandhi to Sherwood Eddy; statement by Gandhi concerning Sherwood Eddy - compiled by E. S. Reddy, 1929-1947 (Box 282, Folder 18)
  - Regan, Catherine (Sr. Mary of St. John Berchmans)
    1872 Feb 16 -Born in Gardner, Massachusetts; 1890 -Graduated from Gardner High School; 1893 -Graduated from Massachusetts State Normal School; 1893-1900 -Taught in Hubbardston, MA, and at School for the Mentally Retarded in Barrie, MA; principal of schools in Gardner, MA; 1900 -Entered convent of the Sisters of the Good Shepherd, Brooklyn, NY; completed noviate at order's mother house in Angers, France; took name Sr. Mary of St. John Berchmans; 1904-1968 -Served at Convent of the Good Shepherd, Norwood, Johannesburg, South Africa. Sr. Mary of St. John Berchmans was "disciplinarian" at a home for "fallen women" and "wayward girls" run by the order.
    - Correspondence to parents and sisters, 1904-1924, n.d. (Box 289)
    - Correspondence to niece, 1921-1950 (Box 289)
    - Correspondence to niece, sisters, 1956-1967 (Box 289)
    - Letters to CR from school girls, 1964 (Box 289)
    - "Catherine Regan - A Massachusetts nun in Johannesburg, 1904-1907 -Excerpts from her letters and postcards"; Typescript booklet edited by William Regan Ahern, Jr., with biographical information and illustrations. (Box 289)
    - Memorabilia related to Good Shepherd Home; Biographical memorabilia, writings of CR; Photographs of CR, n.d. (Box 289)
  - Rexford, Elisha
    Pastor of the Church of Christ in New-Stratford, CT.
    - Manuscript sermon, 1765 (Box 382, Folder 5)
  - Rice, Edwin Botts
    Rice was born in 1853 and died in 1929.
    - Volumes: 1. Missionaries to the China Mission from 1835 to 1901; 2. The Church in Brazil, Cuba, Mexico, Haiti, 1911; 3. Missionaries to the Japan Mission from 1859 to 1901; 4. MIssionaries of the Domestic and Foreign Missionary Society of the Protestant Episcopal Church in the U.S.A., 1909; 5. The Church in the Philippine Islands, 1909; 6. The Church in Alaska, 1914; 7. Missionaries appointed from 1908 to 1913. (Box 93)
      Material consists of seven bound volumes prepared by Rice that contain typescript biographical sketches of missionaries and information regarding churches and missions of the Protestant Episcopal Church. Clippings, photographs, and chronological data are also included.
  - Rigdon, Vernon Bruce, Rigdon, Vernon Bruce, 1936-
    Vernon Bruce Rigdon, born in 1936, is a pastor, social activist and theological educator affiliated with the Presbyterian Church USA. He graduated from Yale Divinity School (B.D. 1962) and Yale University (Ph.D. 1968). He has worked at McCormick Theologial Seminary, Grosse Pointe Farms (Michigan) Presbyterian Church, and Ecumenical Theological Seminary. He has been active in leadership and on several committees with the National Council of Churches (US-USSR Church Relations), World Council of Churches, and World Alliance of Reformed Churches.
    Rigdon, Vernon Bruce, 1936-
    - Documentation of activities
      Meeting and committee records include documentation of the following organizations and events.
      - Choose Life Conference, Geneva, 1979 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Ad Hoc Committee on Relationships between Churches in the USA and the USSR, Karlovy Vary V Consultation, 1981-1982 (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Committee on US/USSR Church Relations, 1983 (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - International Round Table Conference of Religious Workers and Experts, US/USSR Church Relations Committee, USSR Travel Seminar, 1984 (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - USSR Travel Seminar, Karlovy Vary VI, 1984 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - International Round Table Conference of Theologians and Experts, US/USSR Church Relations Program, USSR Travel Seminar, 1985 (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Round Table Conference of Theologians and Scientific Experts, 1987 (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Second International Church Study Conference on the Theology and Spirituality of the Russian Orthodox Church, 1987 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Moscow Dialogue with USSR Church Represenatives, International Orthodox/Reformed Dialogue, National Council of Churches of Christ in the U.S.A. Review, Karlovy Vary VII, Midwest Center for US/USSR Initiatives, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - National Council of Churches of Christ in the USA Unity & Relationships Unit Transition Committee, Meeting of Representatives of the NCCC and Churches in the Soviet Union, Symposium on the Life and Work of Josef L. Hromadka, Midwest Center for US/USSR Initiatives, Orthodox/Reformed Theological Dialogue, 1989 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - Coordinating Committee of the Churches in the Soviet Union and NCCCUSA, Sister Church Program, Center for US/USSR Initiatives, United States Institute of Peace, Orthodox/Reformed Theological Dialogue, 1990 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Europe/USSR Committee, US/USSR Summer Prayer Vigil, Coordinating Committee of the National Council of Churches of Christ in the USA and Churches in the Soviet Union, Muslim, Christian, Jewish Leadership Forum Theologian Trialog, 1991 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Reformed/Eastern Orthodox Dialogue, Muslim, Christian, Jewish Leadership Forum Theologian Trialog, Europe/USSR Committee, Coordinating Committee for the CIS Program, Homes for Christ in Russia, Delegation to the Czech & Slovak Federal Republic, 1992 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - Convocation on A New World Order in Theological Perspective, Midwest Center for US/USSR Initiatives, NCCCUSA General Board & Executive Coordinating Committee, 1992 (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - United Methodist Delegation Visit to The Russian Orthodox Church, Moscow, Europe Committee, Preliminary Report on WCC/CEC Visit to Serbia and Bosnia, Muslim, Christian, Jewish Leadership Forum Scholar Trialog, 1993 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the USA General Board and Related Meetings, Visit to Croatia, 1993 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Reformed/Eastern Orthodox Dialogue Commission, Muslim, Christian, Jewish Leadership Forum Scholar Trialog, Conference on Security and Co-operation in Europe Budapest Summit Declaration, Europe Committee Meeting, 1994 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Association of the Churches' Development Services Working Unit in Central Asia, Midwest Center for Citizen Initiatives - USA, Europe Committee, Albania Round Table, 1995 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - National Council of Churches of Christ in the USA Travel Seminar to Russia and Belarus, Romania Round Table, Europe Committee, 1996 (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - Europe Committee, Second European Ecumenical Assembly - Graz, Austria, World Council of Churches Central Committee, National Council of the Churches of Christ in the USA General Assembly, 1997 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Traveling Seminar on the Russian Orthodox Church, Europe Committee, 1998 (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Europe Committee, Gathering of Pastors of Larger Membership Churches, National Council of Churches of Christ in the USA General Assembly, 1999 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Subject files
      - History of Christianity in the U.S.S.R., National Council of the Churches of Christ in the U.S.A., Muslims of the Soviet East, Billy Graham in the Soviet Union, 1984-1989 (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Reconciliation between the United States and the Soviet Union, 1983-1985 (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Peacemaking, Hunger Relief, Violence Against Women, Reformed-Orthodox Dialogues, 1965-1995 (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Humanitarian Assistance, Evangelism and Ecumenism, Racism and Human Rights, The Armenian Church, Anglican and Eastern Churches Association, 1984-1995 (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Nuclear War, The Waldensian Society, Evangelicals for Middle East Understanding, Cyrillic Alphabet, 1983-1996 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Riggs, Charles Trowbridge
    ABCFM missionary to Turkey; son of Edward and Sarah Dwight Riggs; b 1 Sep 1871 Sivas Turkey d 12 Feb 1953 Istanbul
    - Four letters from Riggs in "Stamboul" to Miss Munger, 1934-1935 (Box 334, Folder 5)
  - Rigobertus, Father
    Fr. Rigobertus served with the Mission Apostolique in Bwamamla, Belgian Congo.
    - Five identified photographs depict missionaries and indigenous people and the Bwamamla Mission, 1931 (Box 303, Folder 27)
  - Ritter, Gerhard
    German conspirator against Hitler
    - Typescript account by Gertrude Ritter of the days her husband, Gerhard Ritter, spent imprisoned in Berlin awaiting execution for his share in a plot against Hitler (in German.) 18 pp., 1945 (Box 334, Folder 6)
  - Robinson, James McConkey
    Robinson (1924-) was professor of religion at the Claremont Graduate School.
    - Photographs of miscellaneous theologians, no date (Box 45, Folder 4)
      IN 2012 Robinson donated to the Yale Divinity School a collection of framed photographic portraits of nineteenth and twentieth century theologians and social philosophers, which are displayed in the Divinity Library Pope Seminar Room. The photographs contained in this collection are primarily snapshots and clippings.
    - Photographs of fragments of scrolls or codices, Biblical texts, no date (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Writings of Willam Childs Robinson and William Childs Robinson, Jr., father and brother of JCR, 1957-1964 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Materials related to Tagung Alter Marburger meetings, 1954-1960 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Rogers, Miriam E.
    Miriam Rogers was a native of Cleveland, Ohio who served as a missionary in India under the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions Marathi Mission. She first went to India from 1937 to 1949 and was involved in educational and child welfare work, stationed in Sholapur and Bombay. She contracted polio while in India and came back to the U.S. for rehabilitation. She returned to India in September, 1951 and served there under the ABCFM / United Church Board for World Ministries through the 1970s in Mahableshwar and Sholapur.
    - Circular letters of Rogers, 1944-1977, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
    - Circular letters of others: B - V (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
    - Letters of Rogers to family, 1933-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Letters of Rogers to others: Franklin, Harmon (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Writings by Rogers (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Diary of Rogers; article about her (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Collected material re. ABCFM American Marathi Mission (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Collected material: programs and misc. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Rowley, Patrick
    Rowley was a missionary in Sarawak, Borneo, serving under the Society for the Propagation of the Gospel.
    - Two mimeographed circular letters and the second page of a third one describe Rowley family's arrival in Borneo and the Farm School project, agricultural work supported by Inter Church Aid., 1962 (Box 282, Folder 8)
  - Royer, Galen B.
    Royer was Secretary of the Mission Board of the Church of the Brethren. In 1913-1914 he traveled to Europe, Russia, Persia, Siberia, Manchuria, China, and India.
    - Report letters from travels, 1913-1914 (Box 326)
  - Ryan, Vincent William
    Ryan (1816–1888)was the first Anglican bishop of the Mauritius.
    - Handwritten letter from Ryan to The Lord Bishop of Carlyle discusses mission work in Mauritius, 1856 May 12 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Scheel, Richard and Margaret
    The Scheels were missionaries in Ethiopia serving under SIM (Sudan Interior Mission).
    - Three letters from the Scheels and two additional letters related to missions in Ethiopia, 1970-1973 (Box 303, Folder 33)
  - Schoonmaker, M. V.
    Schoonmaker was a missionary in India serving under the Assemblies of God.
    - One typescript letter to a friend and two photographs of Indian children who have received toys from the Mission, 1940 (Box 303, Folder 34)
  - Schrading, Paul E.
    Schrading received a B.D. from Yale Divinity School in 1958. He was involved in the student Christian movement both as a student and as a professional. As a student he held several offices in the National Student Committee of the YMCA from 1952-1955, and was Chairman of the USCC in 1956-57. As a professional, Schrading was the Associate General Secretary of University Christian Movement from 1966-1967, and became General Secretary of the UCM in 1968. A collection of his files can be found in the UCM records, Record Group 235..
    - Letter from Herluf Jensen expressing thanks for Schrading's leadership in the United Student Christian Council, October 1, 1957 (Box 250, Folder 1)
    - Letter to Ed Nestingen re. worship service at YMCA National Student Assembly, includes worship service, February 16, 1955 (Box 250, Folder 2)
    - National Student Council of the YMCA and YWCA: assembly work books, newsletters, papers, and reports; Including "Collegiate Christian Movements in 1953" by William A. Overholt and "The Task of the Student Christian Movement: Presented as a basic statement for all committees considering business relative to USCC", 1950-1956 (Box 250, Folder 3)
    - National Student Council of the YMCA and YWCA: study booklets; Including "Faith, Sex, and Love" by William Hamilton and "Being a Woman" by Fern Babcock, 1954-1955 (Box 250, Folder 4)
    - Photograph of National Student Christina Federation officers Elmira Kendricks, Bruce Douglas, Stanley Skinner, and Cherly Wiley, 1964 (Box 250, Folder 5)
    - Theology and Revolution: articles, journals, papers, and reports; Including Christianity and Revolution journal published at Union Theological Seminary, 1966-1969 (Box 250, Folder 6)
    - Untitled thesis by unknown author re. history of the United Student Christian Council, undated (Box 250, Folder 7)
    - Who Rules Columbia: booklets and report; Including Why We Strike published by the Columbia Strike Committee., 1968 (Box 250, Folder 8)
    - World Student Christian Federation: directories, mailing lists, and newspaper clippings, 1956-1960 (Box 250, Folder 9)
    - WSCF General Committee minutes, 1956, 1960, 1964, 1968 (Box 250, Folder 10)
    - WSCF: Preliminary and Incomplete Four-Year Report on the Life and Work of the WSCF, 1968 (Box 250, Folder 11)
    - YMCA: student council addresses, 1965 (Box 250, Folder 12)
  - Schubert, Paul
    1900 Oct. 9 - Born in Hanover, Germany; 1920 - Ph.D. Bonn; 1935 - Ph.D. University of Chicago; 1946, 1947 - Visiting Professor of New Testament, Yale; 1949-1950 - Professor of New Testament Language and Literature, Yale; 1950-1968 - Buckingham Professor of New Testament Criticism and Interpretation, Yale; 1968 - D.D. Berkeley Divinity School; 1969 Dec 16 - Died in Falmouth, Massachusetts
    - Correspondence: primarily regarding professional activities, 1933-1967 (Box 60)
    - Articles by Schubert: arranged alphabetically by title: B - R, 1929-1968 (Box 60)
    - Articles by Schubert: arranged alphabetically by title: S (Box 61)
    - Lectures: arranged alphabetically, 1941-1955, n.d. (Box 62)
    - Untitled manuscript, n.d. (Box 62)
    - Notes, 1928-1954, n.d. (Box 62)
    - Notes (Box 63)
    - Writings by others (Box 64)
    - Miscellaneous material regarding World Council of Churches and Society of Biblical Literature and Exegesis (Box 64)
    - Material related to Schubert's position on the General Editorial Board and General Executive Committee of the International Greek New Testament Project (Box 64)
    - 2 loose leaf volumes: "Luke: Index of Readings" (Box 65)
  - Schupp, Ronald
    Schupp (1951-) was a clergyman and civil rights leader. Biographical information is available in the first folder.
    - Photocopies of letters from Nelson Mandela, Coretta Scott King, Desmond Tutu, and others, newsclippings, and citations in support of Schupp's annual fast and vigil for the end of Apartheid., 1992-1995 (Box 282, Folder 1)
  - Scourfield, Tegwen
    Scourfield was a missionary in Baglung, Nepal.
    - Diary for 1962 with detailed daily entries describing her activities at a medical dispensary in Baglung, Nepal (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Sedgwick, T.
    - Two ms. sermons delivered in Brampton, MA, 1692 Sep (Box 215, Folder 4)
  - Seiple, W. H.
    Missionary serving under Christian and Missionary Alliance, Soudan Mission, Sierra Leone, Africa ca. 1895-1902.
    - Handwritten journal describing experiences and mission work in Africa. (91 pp.), ca. 1895 (Box 334, Folder 8)
    - Glass plate negative: scene with natives in Africa (Box 334, Folder 9)
  - Seys Family
    John Seys may have been superintendent of the Liberian Mission of the Methodist Episcopal Church around 1844.
    - Primarily correspondence: Letters are from family members during periods of separation when the father, John Seys, was in Liberia, Africa, or away on preaching trips in New York and Pennsylvania. Most of the letters are addressed to John Seys, Ann Seys (his wife), or Mary Seys (their daughter). A few letters are from M. R. and Catherine Garrettson, who cared for Mary Seys; biographical information about John Seys, his funeral services, geneaology of Seys family, 1830-1872, n.d. (Box 112)
  - Shepard, Henry B.
    After graduating from Yale College in 1949, Shepard taught at the American University in Cairo, and then was assistant director of the International Student House at the University of Goettingen in Germany in 1950 and 1951. He later attended Harvard Lae School and was an attorney in Boston. These records document Shepard's involvement with the Student Christian Movement while at Yale, with the World Student Christian Federation, and his ongoing financial support for the University Christian Movement in New England.
    - Re. SCM-sponsored O-At-Ka Conferences, incl. 1947 address by Adelaide Case, lists of participants, songs, games, letter of HBS reminiscing about conference, 1947-1949, 2001 (Box 387, Folder 1)
    - Re. American University of Cairo, incl. list of American personnel 1950/1951, 1950, n.d. (Box 387, Folder 2)
    - Re. World Student Christian Federation European Leaders Conferences, 1951-1952 (Box 387, Folder 3)
    - Misc. letters and leaflets re. student Christian work, incl. World University Service, 1947-1952, n.d. (Box 387, Folder 4)
    - Letters, reports re. status and financial support of University Christian Movement in New England, incl. list of alumni, 1985-1991 (Box 387, Folder 5)
    - Letters, reports re. status and financial support of UCMNE, incl. "Momentum" newsletter, 1992-1995 (Box 387, Folder 6)
    - Letters, reports re. status and financial support of UCMNE, incl. re. dissolution of UCMNE in December 2000., 1996-2001 (Box 387, Folder 7)
    - Circular letters, directories re. World Student Christian Federation Senior Friends, 1994-1996 (Box 387, Folder 8)
    - Photographs: Yale Hope Mission Board (ca. 1946); Yale College, Jonathan Edwards Intercollegiate Soccer Champs (1945); Yale Community Council (1946, 1947); two snapshots of students in Europe (1950), 1946-1950 (Box 387, Folder 9)
    - Membership certificate and ID card, Miniature Tree Growers' Association, 1947 (Box 387, Folder 10)
  - Shepard, Lorrin A.
    Medical doctor, Director of American Hospital of Istanbul, Turkey; leader of Istanbul American Hospital Relief Unit
    - Typescript journal covering the trip of the Istanbul American Hospital Relief Unit, in association with the Turkish Red Crescent's Society's 2nd Emergency Hospital sent to the Turkish earthquake zone, 1940 Jan - Feb (Box 334, Folder 7)
  - Sherrill, Edwin Jenner and Sarah Foote
    1806 Oct 23 - Edwin Jenner Sherrill: Born in Shoreham, VT; 1833 - B.A., Hamilton College; 1834-1835 - studied at Andover Theological Seminary; 1837 - Graduated from Yale Divinity School; 1838-1875 - Ordained, served as minister of Congregational Church in Eaton, Canada; 1838 Oct 1 - Married Sarah Foote (d. 1885), who had taught at Ipswich Seminary; 1875-1877 - Resided in Lee, MA; 1877 Jun 13 - Died in New York City.
    - Journals of Edwin Jenner Sherrill: Vol. 1: 1846 Jan - 1848 Dec; Vol. 2: 1861 May - 1868 Mar; Vol. 3: 1868 Mar - 1870 Aug; Unbound sheets: 1870 Sep - 1871 Nov; Vol. 4: 1873 Jan - 1874 Aug (Box 306)
    - Common Place Book of Sarah Foote, Ipswich, 1834-1835 (Box 306)
    - Bound volume: "Records of the Maternal Association of Eaton, L. Canada, Organized June 2, 1840" (Box 306)
    - Newspaper article: "The Old Church at Eaton", 1905 (Box 306)